{
    "title": "Psychology Quiz",
    "total": 26,
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What is psychology?",
            "options": [
                "The study of physical health and exercise.",
                "The analysis of weather patterns and their effects.",
                "The branch of science that studies how the brain works and how the mind influences behavior in people and animals.",
                "The study of ancient artifacts and cultures."
            ],
            "score": 1,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What makes us choose one choice over the other?",
            "options": [
                "Random chance",
                "Behavioral Psychology",
                "Genetic predisposition",
                "The alignment of stars"
            ],
            "score": 3,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "How is the brain the control system of the body?",
            "options": [
                "It controls only muscle movements.",
                "It stores all nutrients and energy for the body.",
                "It processes food and nutrients for the body.",
                "The brain receives signals from the rest of the body & makes sense of them."
            ],
            "score": 3,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the cerebrum do?",
            "options": [
                "Helps us interpret the world around us with memory, vision, hearing, and our senses.",
                "Controls digestion and waste elimination.",
                "Regulates heart rate and blood pressure.",
                "Manages muscle reflexes and coordination."
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the cerebellum do?",
            "options": [
                "Processes emotional responses.",
                "Conducts motor functions like muscle movement & balance.",
                "Controls language and communication.",
                "Manages hunger and thirst."
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the brain stem do?",
            "options": [
                "Controls thoughts and decision-making.",
                "Regulates vision and hearing.",
                "Manages sensory perceptions.",
                "Conducts necessary functions like breathing, heart rate, etc."
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What did Freudian Psychology do?",
            "options": [
                "Studied the effects of diet on mental health.",
                "Focused on brain chemistry and medication.",
                "Emphasized the importance of childhood memories on the brain.",
                "Analyzed animal behavior and instincts."
            ],
            "score": 3,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What makes us fall for mind tricks?",
            "options": [
                "Visual and auditory illusions.",
                "Speed of Processing and Selective Attention Theory.",
                "Influence of external stimuli.",
                "Changes in atmospheric pressure."
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you make a short term memory?",
            "options": [
                "Feel/See something and have it registered in your brain.",
                "Write down information repeatedly.",
                "Dream about an event.",
                "Perform a physical activity."
            ],
            "score": 1,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "How long can memories stay in short term memory for?",
            "options": [
                "Several hours.",
                "A few days.",
                "Several weeks.",
                "20-30 seconds."
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What animal was the hippocampus named after?",
            "options": [
                "Dolphin.",
                "Whale.",
                "Seahorse.",
                "Octopus."
            ],
            "score": 1,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What makes a memory long term?",
            "options": [
                "Experiencing it once.",
                "Experiencing the memory more than once.",
                "Forgetting it initially.",
                "Reading about it in a book."
            ],
            "score": 1,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What is memory fading?",
            "options": [
                "When you stop reviewing the memory, it fades from your memory and gets replaced.",
                "When memories get stronger over time.",
                "When memories become more vivid and detailed.",
                "When new memories are created quickly."
            ],
            "score": 1,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "What is targeted forgetting?",
            "options": [
                "The inability to remember anything.",
                "Remembering only selective details.",
                "Learn new information that is different to old information and 'Delete' old information while you sleep.",
                "Forgetting all information from the past month."
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 2
        }
    ]
}
